so let's see if we understood the impact
of branch pictors on performance we will
consider the old penum 4 prescod
processor which has an extremely deep
pipeline it fetches then does 29 stages
worth of work and only then it resolves
branches it of course uses Branch
friction and is capable of executing
multiple instructions per cycle so that
in a program where about 20% of all
instructions are branches only 1% of
branches might be mispredicted and let's
say that that gives us a CPI on this
program of
0.5 so the question for you is if we had
a slightly worse predictor so that 2% of
branches are mispredicted in this
program how would that change the CPI
what would the CPI be